<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="definition">
        The term “chronic kidney disease” means lasting damage to the kidneys that can get worse over time. If the damage is very bad, your kidneys may stop working. This is called kidney failure, or end-stage renal disease (ESRD). If your kidneys fail, you will need dialysis or a kidney transplant in order to live.</string>
    <string name="definition1">The liver plays an important role in many bodily functions from protein production and blood clotting to cholesterol, glucose (sugar), and iron metabolism.
A variety of illnesses can affect the liver, for example,
certain drugs like excessive amounts of acetaminophen, and acetaminophen combination medications like Vicodin, Norco, and statins,
cirrhosis,
alcohol abuse,
hepatitis A, B, C, D, and E,
Epstein Barr virus (infectious mononucleosis),
non-alcoholic fatty liver disease,
iron overload (hemochromatosis),</string>
    <string name="definition2">Gum disease is an inflammation of the gum line that can progress to affect the bone that surrounds and supports your teeth. The three stages of gum disease — from least to most severe — are gingivitis, periodontitis and advanced periodontitis.</string>
    <string name="definition3">Mouth sores are common ailments that affect many at some point in their lives.

These sores can appear on any of the soft tissues of your mouth, including your lips, cheeks, gums, tongue, and floor and roof of your mouth. You can even develop mouth sores on your esophagus, the tube leading to your stomach.

Mouth sores — which include canker sores — are usually a minor irritation and last only a week or two. In some cases, however, they can indicate mouth cancer or an infection from a virus, such as herpes simplex.

Herpes simplex causes cold sores, or fever blisters, and is highly contagious. The sores are contagious until completely healed, so be sure to wash your hands after touching them and to change your toothbrush once they’re healed.</string>

<string name="definition4">Cancer is the uncontrolled growth of abnormal cells anywhere in a body.
There are over 200 types of cancer.
Anything that may cause a normal body cell to develop abnormally potentially can cause cancer; general categories of cancer-related or causative agents are as follows: chemical or toxic compound exposures, ionizing radiation, some pathogens, and human genetics.</string>

<string name="definition5">Diabetes, often referred to by doctors as diabetes mellitus, describes a group of metabolic diseases in which the person has high blood glucose (blood sugar), either because insulin production is inadequate, or because the bodys cells do not respond properly to insulin, or both. Patients with high blood sugar will typically experience polyuria (frequent urination), they will become increasingly thirsty (polydipsia) and hungry (polyphagia).

    <string name="definition6">Cancer is defined as the uncontrollable growth of cells that invade and cause damage to surrounding tissue. Oral cancer appears as a growth or sore in the mouth that does not go away. Oral cancer, which includes cancers of the lips, tongue, cheeks, floor of the mouth, hard and soft palate, sinuses, and pharynx (throat), can be life threatening if not diagnosed and treated early.</string>
Fast facts on diabetes</string>

</resources>